Thank you,
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Director. Great to see you here on the Hill again. Appreciate the work you and your team do to protect America's consumers and, frankly, to clarify the law as it exists. Frankly, one of the concerns that we've had in the structure that's been shared across the aisles is everything depends on who the director is. And we really do need to change that structure, as has been highlighted by a number of members. But frankly, the concern I had is the previous director.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): uh reflected poorly on our state of ohio by uh his practices whether it was hiring practices or sue and settle schemes or frankly ways to make companies settle even in spite of the law so providing clarity not just for the consumers but for the businesses that are trying in uh in their best efforts to serve consumers so thank you for that i truly believe um that that a lot of it does go back to consumer education in terms of financial education and you can really
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): see the difference that it makes certainly compounding interest has changed the world and changes the world for all sorts of people whether that's working for good to accumulate wealth over time or working for bad to see people get on the wrong side of that debt so appreciate your efforts there I want to highlight a couple things as you sit in a role that was created in a way to kind of sit over top
of
you
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): know, broadly things that are already bad practices in every single state. So it's not like most of the things that I'm hearing people criticize you for here today aren't against the law in every state in the United States of America. And attorneys generals are prosecuting people for the criminal activity there. And so systemically, as you look across the entire financial sector of the United States from the federal level, I'm just curious, what position are you
in to assess
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): couple things. So when you look at things that can pass as a member of the minority, maybe we can study something, something that's bipartisan. So when you look at faster payments and you look at FinTech and all the innovation that's out there and now the Fed's newfound interest in the Fed itself taking a role in faster payments, do you have a way to assess
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): the transaction costs that consumers are paying just as a means of payment, whether that's credit card fees or processing fees, money transmittal fees,
Speaker 2: but all the ways that people would move money between one another, how many fees are they
paying?
I can
Speaker 3: tell you, Congressman, that I can't, of course, answer that quite direct question at this particular
Speaker 4: moment, but the Atlantic Fed does do extensive research and surveys on payments, and they kind of have the center of gravity on some of this research, so we have been working with them on making sure that we're looking at what's happening in this marketplace and understanding, again, the dynamics. I...
If I
Speaker 4: go too much further, I may misspeak, but we can get back to you with some of the summaries of the research and what we've seen. Perfect.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): And one of the other areas that I think is a shared sense of concern in Congress and across the United States is consumers' data. So we've really failed in Congress, in my opinion, to do our duty and provide a data privacy regulation, a standard that's really foundational, really, to our consumers.
I
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): mean, it's supposed to be there in a sense, the right to privacy in the Fourth Amendment. But as times have changed, we haven't really updated it for the electronic era, for sure. And we've seen companies that have collected and monetized lots of personally identifiable information. And unfortunately, sometimes compromised that data. So as you look at how we
know companies
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): have monetized the data.
When
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): that data is compromised, what are the impacts on consumers? Would you be in a position to assess that? So
we have with
Speaker 5: respect to a couple of
Speaker 4: different enforcement actions, but I can say there are some lines amongst the federal agencies over authorities in this space. For example, Congress explicitly took the GLBA safeguards out of the Bureau's purview. The Federal Trade Commission has that responsibility in addition with the prudential regulators. But I will say holistically,
certainly,
Speaker 4: We are looking at what's happening in this space, and we are certainly doing our part. Perhaps
Speaker 6: from the consumer's perspective. Yeah. So thank you for that. And then I think the last thing is just in the interest of the QM rule
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): and the upcoming piece, you know, you're not yet into the rulemaking, but you're talking about going towards it. Certainly that says there are things that you have concerns about the rule as it exists today. And, you know, I guess what kinds of things are you and the staff there trying to balance as you look at a review of this, the interest, things that are broken and things that you want to safeguard? And clarify. Well,
that's
Speaker 4: definitely a longer question probably that I can answer in a shorter period of time. I would say very clearly carrying out the law, there is a requirement to have an ability to repay and how that's determined. Thank
Speaker 7: you.